<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-08-30T11:10:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Lisa-Monique Edward</title><subtitle>Resume/Portfolio for Lisa-Monique Edward</subtitle><author><name>Lisa-Monique Edward</name></author><entry><title type="html">Undergraduate Student</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2018/08/20/Undergraduate-Student.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Undergraduate Student" /><published>2018-08-20T21:17:11-04:00</published><updated>2018-08-20T21:17:11-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2018/08/20/Undergraduate-Student</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2018/08/20/Undergraduate-Student.html">&lt;div class=&quot;desc info&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I'm currently an undergraduate student pursuing a Bachelor of Medical Sciences with an Honours Specialisation in Computational Biochemistry. Current average: 86%&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Accomplishments&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;ul style=&quot;margin-left: 20px;&quot;&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Placed on 2016/2017 and 2017/2018 Dean's Honor Lists for attaining A average&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Awarded International President's Entrance Scholarship as part of the University's National Scholarship Program after a rigorous application and interview process. 1 of 3 students. Value: $50,000 CAD&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Selected as 1 of 50 incoming students to be part of the prestigious Scholar's Electives program: a research-intensive interdisciplinary-learning program which runs concurrently with academics&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Activities &amp;amp; Societies&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;ul style=&quot;margin-left: 20px;&quot;&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Women in Technology Society&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Scientific Research Society&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Western Women in Leadership Club&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Caribbean Students' Organization&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Biology Undergraduate Society&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Computer Science Undergraduate Society&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Amnesty International&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Noteworthy Courses&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;row&quot; style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;col-sm-3 col-xs-6&quot;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;four-piece&quot; style=&quot;background-image: url(../images/computer-science.jpg);&quot;&gt;
                91%
            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Data Structures &amp;amp; Algorithms&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;col-sm-3 col-xs-6&quot;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;four-piece&quot; style=&quot;background-image: url(../images/biochemistry.jpg);&quot;&gt;
                90%
            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Intro to Biochemical Research&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;col-sm-3 col-xs-6&quot;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;four-piece&quot; style=&quot;background-image: url(../images/math.jpg);&quot;&gt;
                96%
            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Linear Algebra I&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;col-sm-3 col-xs-6&quot;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;four-piece&quot; style=&quot;background-image: url(../images/leadership.png);&quot;&gt;
                90%
            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Exploring Leadership&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Lisa-Monique Edward</name></author><summary type="html">I'm currently an undergraduate student pursuing a Bachelor of Medical Sciences with an Honours Specialisation in Computational Biochemistry. Current average: 86% Accomplishments Placed on 2016/2017 and 2017/2018 Dean's Honor Lists for attaining A average Awarded International President's Entrance Scholarship as part of the University's National Scholarship Program after a rigorous application and interview process. 1 of 3 students. Value: $50,000 CAD Selected as 1 of 50 incoming students to be part of the prestigious Scholar's Electives program: a research-intensive interdisciplinary-learning program which runs concurrently with academics Activities &amp;amp; Societies Women in Technology Society Scientific Research Society Western Women in Leadership Club Caribbean Students' Organization Biology Undergraduate Society Computer Science Undergraduate Society Amnesty International Noteworthy Courses 91% Data Structures &amp;amp; Algorithms 90% Intro to Biochemical Research 96% Linear Algebra I 90% Exploring Leadership</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Summer Research Student</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/08/20/Summer-Research-Student.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Summer Research Student" /><published>2018-08-20T21:17:10-04:00</published><updated>2018-08-20T21:17:10-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/08/20/Summer-Research-Student</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/08/20/Summer-Research-Student.html">&lt;div class=&quot;about&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot; info&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;This summer I participated in the SickKids Summer Research (SSuRe) program in the lab of Dr. Adam Shlien (Associate Director, Translational Genetics, DPLM; Scientist, Genetics and Genome Biology; co-Director, KiCS cancer sequencing program). This lab uses the tools of modern sequence-based genomics to discover the mutations that are present in the genomes of paediatric cancer patients, and is directly involved with the  introduction of cutting-edge genomics, such as whole genome sequencing, into clinical practice.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;For my project, I wrote a variety of Python and R scripts in order to draw useful insights from a large dataset of over 450,000 DNA probes and over 5,000 cancer samples spanning 31 cancer types. I presented my findings in the form of a written abstract as well as a poster presentation.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Lisa-Monique Edward</name></author><summary type="html">This summer I participated in the SickKids Summer Research (SSuRe) program in the lab of Dr. Adam Shlien (Associate Director, Translational Genetics, DPLM; Scientist, Genetics and Genome Biology; co-Director, KiCS cancer sequencing program). This lab uses the tools of modern sequence-based genomics to discover the mutations that are present in the genomes of paediatric cancer patients, and is directly involved with the introduction of cutting-edge genomics, such as whole genome sequencing, into clinical practice. For my project, I wrote a variety of Python and R scripts in order to draw useful insights from a large dataset of over 450,000 DNA probes and over 5,000 cancer samples spanning 31 cancer types. I presented my findings in the form of a written abstract as well as a poster presentation.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Generation Google Scholar</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/08/20/Generation-Google-Scholar.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Generation Google Scholar" /><published>2018-08-20T21:17:09-04:00</published><updated>2018-08-20T21:17:09-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/08/20/Generation-Google-Scholar</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/08/20/Generation-Google-Scholar.html">&lt;div class=&quot;desc info&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I am one of 15 recipients in the North American region or the Generation Google Scholarship for 2018 (Value: $5,000 CAD). This scholarship supports students from historically underrepresented groups in tech and aims to inspire and help them become future leaders and role models in computing and technology by breaking down the barriers that prevent them from entering these fields. The scholarship recognizes students for academic excellence, exceptional leadership, demonstrating a passion for technology and acting as a role model within their community. As a recipient of this scholarship for the 2018 cycle, I attended the 2018 Google Scholar Retreat at the Googleplex in Mountain View, CA in August.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Lisa-Monique Edward</name></author><summary type="html">I am one of 15 recipients in the North American region or the Generation Google Scholarship for 2018 (Value: $5,000 CAD). This scholarship supports students from historically underrepresented groups in tech and aims to inspire and help them become future leaders and role models in computing and technology by breaking down the barriers that prevent them from entering these fields. The scholarship recognizes students for academic excellence, exceptional leadership, demonstrating a passion for technology and acting as a role model within their community. As a recipient of this scholarship for the 2018 cycle, I attended the 2018 Google Scholar Retreat at the Googleplex in Mountain View, CA in August.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">SheHacks II Organizer</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/08/20/SheHacks-II-Organizer.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SheHacks II Organizer" /><published>2018-08-20T21:17:08-04:00</published><updated>2018-08-20T21:17:08-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/08/20/SheHacks-II-Organizer</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/08/20/SheHacks-II-Organizer.html">&lt;div class=&quot;about info&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;On March 25th, 2018, the Women in Technology Society (WiTS) hosted 150 women from across Canada for Western University's first and only hackathon designed to encourage women in tech: SheHacks.  Over the past year, I was the Communications Director of WiTS and therefore had the opportunity to help organize SheHacks II.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The mission of WiTS is to encourage, connect, and inspire women to explore the technology industry and SheHacks II was created to encourage women* from all backgrounds and skill sets to attend a hackathon in a fun, safe, and inclusive environment.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;SheHacks II by the numbers&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: none;&quot;&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-female&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; 150 hackers&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;far fa-hourglass-half&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; 12 hours&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-trophy&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; $5,000 in prizes&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-sign-in-alt&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; 32 project submissions&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-money-bill-alt&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; 25 sponsors&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Responsibilities&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
         &lt;li&gt;Produced monthly MailChimp newsletter for WiTS and informational newsletters related to SheHacks&lt;/li&gt;
         &lt;li&gt;Managed society's social media and website&lt;/li&gt;  
         &lt;li&gt;Designed marketing material including social media graphics and event posters. Of note, I designed the presentations used for opening and closing remarks of the hackathon, standing banners used at the event and all promotional material related to the event.&lt;/li&gt;   
    &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;div style=&quot;padding-left: 20px;&quot;&gt;
        &lt;h4&gt;Recap video&lt;/h4&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;resp-container&quot;&gt;
            &lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/plugins/video.php?href=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2Fwits.uwo%2Fvideos%2F771084993088045%2F&amp;amp;show_text=0&amp;amp;width=560&quot; style=&quot;border:none;overflow:hidden&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowtransparency=&quot;true&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; class=&quot;resp-iframe&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Lisa-Monique Edward</name></author><summary type="html">On March 25th, 2018, the Women in Technology Society (WiTS) hosted 150 women from across Canada for Western University's first and only hackathon designed to encourage women in tech: SheHacks. Over the past year, I was the Communications Director of WiTS and therefore had the opportunity to help organize SheHacks II. The mission of WiTS is to encourage, connect, and inspire women to explore the technology industry and SheHacks II was created to encourage women* from all backgrounds and skill sets to attend a hackathon in a fun, safe, and inclusive environment. SheHacks II by the numbers 150 hackers 12 hours $5,000 in prizes 32 project submissions 25 sponsors Responsibilities Produced monthly MailChimp newsletter for WiTS and informational newsletters related to SheHacks Managed society's social media and website Designed marketing material including social media graphics and event posters. Of note, I designed the presentations used for opening and closing remarks of the hackathon, standing banners used at the event and all promotional material related to the event. Recap video</summary></entry></feed>